<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">

    <channel>
        <title>Rene Hlavova: Expeditions</title>
        <link>https://expeditions.renehlavova.com</link>
        <description>travel photo blog of my nomadic life</description>
        <item>
            <title>Happy Island: Active Holidays on the Island of Rab</title>
            <link>
                https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/happy-island-active-holidays-on-the-island-of-rab</link>
            <description>Every year, we look forward to spending our holidays in Croatia, exploring
                different islands.Last year, we visited Ugljan; this year we randomly picked Rab. We
                like the slow island life, so we chose a location in northern Croatia to shorten our
                travel time.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Austrian Alps: Trail to Schafberg</title>
            <link>https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/austrian-alps-trail-to-schafberg</link>
            <description>Me and my friend travelled to Austria this spring. With the weather being
                unpredictable at this time of the year, we were looking for a hiking trail that
                would be safe but challenging at the same time. Schafberg seemed to fit the bill
                perfectly. The altitude is not too high (1,783 m), but you essentially have to hike
                all the way up from Wolfgangsee. Schafberg is a mountain peak surrounded by three
                Austrian lakes - Mondsee, Attersee, and Wolfgangsee.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Easter Holidays in Switzerland: Walensee and Zürich</title>
            <link>
                https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/easter-holidays-in-switzerland-walensee-and-zurich</link>
            <description>Only five-hour ride, that didn't take long to decide for a roadtrip to
                Switzerland during Easter. We picked the nearest place with a lake in the Alps which
                happens to be Walensee. Although random, it turned out to be an amazing choice! The
                lake is amazing and there are many hiking routes and destinations around the lake.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Saxon Switzerland: Autumn Hiking Trails</title>
            <link>https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/saxon-switzerland-autumn-hiking-trails</link>
            <description>Two years ago, we hiked through Saxon Switzerland with my best friend
                during autumn while sleeping in the car. We were lucky that we had sunny weather
                throughout the whole trip, so the sceneries were truly beautiful in this part of the
                year. We arrived late afternoon to Pfaffendorf to do a quick hike to catch a sunset
                from Pfaffenstein (trail here).</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Roadtrip to Poland: What to see around Krakow</title>
            <link>https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/roadtrip-to-poland-what-to-see-around-krakow</link>
            <description>This trip to Poland was one of those random roadtrips we made because it
                was the only place nearby where it did not rain. And since we didn't want to waste
                our holidays, we headed east with no plan in mind.Recently, I bought a new ND filter
                which is the reason this post will contain mostly portraits and weird experiments. I
                mostly shoot landscapes but change is always a good practice ☺︎Also the photos were
                taken a year ago. It is crazy to see how much I progressed or changed my color
                grading and taste in general.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>High Tatras: Koprovsky Stit Hiking Trail</title>
            <link>https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/high-tatras-koprovsky-stit-hiking-trail</link>
            <description>July was the perfect month to go hiking in Slovak High Tatras. Our aim was
                to hike up the Koprovsky Stit (2,363 m). The hike starts at a large parking lot at
                Strbske pleso and takes you around several other lakes. It has a total elevation of
                approximately 1,100 m.The hike takes around 9-10 hours depending on your fitness
                level.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Exploring Ugljan: Holidays on the Dalmatian Islands</title>
            <link>
                https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/exploring-ugljan-holidays-on-the-dalmatian-islands</link>
            <description>Ugljan is a Dalmatian Island connected by a ferry to Zadar. We stayed in
                Lukoran which is a 1-hour walk from Preko (or 5 minutes by car ☺︎ ). All the places
                mentioned in this article are also available in the following google map.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tenerife Nomad Part II: East Coast and Anaga Park</title>
            <link>
                https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/tenerife-nomad-part-ii-east-coast-and-anaga-park</link>
            <description>After two weeks exploring northern part of Tenerife (which you can read
                more about here), we moved to another location in Anaga Park. We wanted to do some
                more hiking and enjoy calm holidays in San Andres. </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tenerife Nomad Part I: North Coast and Teide Park</title>
            <link>
                https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/tenerife-nomad-part-i-north-coast-and-teide-park</link>
            <description>February tends to be very cold in Czech republic so we decided to head to
                tropical Canary islands - Tenerife. We will be spending the first two weeks
                exploring the northern part with our base in Los Realejos. It is close to Puerto de
                Cruz with good bus connections, it is surrounded by huge mountains and green
                landscape.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Two-Week Roadtrip in Greece: Top 3 Places to Visit</title>
            <link>
                https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/two-week-roadtrip-in-greece-top-3-places-to-visit</link>
            <description>Last year in September, we spent two weeks roadtripping around Greece,
                sleeping in campsites in a tiny Kia Ceed. I put up together a map with the route and
                all the places we visited. I must say two weeks are definitely not enough to visit
                all the beautiful places in Greece, but anyways was very well worth it.In this
                article, I choose my top three places from the whole trip that I recommend everyone
                to visit. </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Roadtrip to North Tyrol: Stunning Lake Hiking Trails</title>
            <link>
                https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/roadtrip-to-north-tyrol-stunning-lake-hiking-trails</link>
            <description>In May 2023, me and my best friend went to see Tyrol for the first time.
                And it was definitely not the last. The landscapes were just stunning. Hey, you'll
                see.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>One-Week Itinerary for Dublin in Autumn</title>
            <link>https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/one-week-itinerary-for-dublin-autumn</link>
            <description>October 2022, I visited a friend in Dublin. I spent most of the days hiking
                and drinking coffee, and I am glad that I managed to squeeze most of the natural
                wonders in one single week. I did not have a car, so I travelled mostly using public
                transport, though me and my friend also did one tour to the west coast.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Winter Hiking in Jizera Mountains and Jested</title>
            <link>https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/winter-hiking-in-jizera-mountains-and-jested</link>
            <description>Last winter, me and my friend stayed in Liberec to explore the Jizera
                mountains along with Jested. Jizera mountains are located on the border between
                Czechia and Poland. </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Weekend Trip to Budapest</title>
            <link>https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/weekend-trip-to-budapest</link>
            <description>This weekend was all about coffee and food.BudapestBudapest reminded me of
                home in many aspects. It is just 4 hours away from Czechia by train. Architecture
                and vibe was similar to Prague, tiny streets looked almost as walking through Brno.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Digital Nomading in Madeira</title>
            <link>https://expeditions.renehlavova.com/digital-nomading-in-madeira</link>
            <description>One year ago, I spent a month working remotely from Madeira. As much as I
                love autumn, November is a dark, grey, and cold month in Czechia so I decided to
                leave. MachicoI decided to spend my first week in Machico as I prefer remote,
                uncrowded places. I stayed at a place near the viewpoint Miradouro Francisco Alvares
                Nóbrega where I often took a shortcut down to the centre. There were almost no
                pavements around the city, but I quickly noticed that I'm probably the only one
                walking around these hills. Drivers were staring at me when I was walking to the
                groceries ☺︎​​​​​​​</description>
        </item>
    </channel>

</rss>